A Guide to the Richard Corbin Papers, 1746-1825
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg
Richard Corbin Papers, 1746-1825.
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
DMS 1971.5
3 volumes and 370 items.
Richard Corbin, ca. 1708-1790.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, 1971.
Alternative Form
Also available on microfilm M-1559 and M-1560.
Biographical/Historical Information
Richard Corbin (ca. 1708-1790) served as a burgess, councillor, and receiver general of Virginia, 1761-1776.
Scope and Content Information
Letters and accounts of Richard Corbin. Included are warrants for payments from the Virginia quitrents; accounts and letters with Osgood and Capel Hanbury, his London agents; memoranda and accounts regarding his plantations; accounts with tradesmen; and accounts, legal papers, and letters to his son, Richard Corbin, Jr., which comprise most of the later material.
The three volumes include Corbin's letterbook, 1758-1768, with copies of letters and invoices to Edward Athawes, Lt. Gov. Robert Dinwiddie, the Hanburys, Edmund Jenings, Philip Ludwell, John Roberts, Ralph Wormeley, Charles Goore, the Rev. Beilby Porteus, and others; his tobacco book, 1746-1790, recording annual quantity, origin, place of inspection, disposition, and overseers' shares; and the diary of John Harrower, 1773-1776, Scottish indentured tutor of Col. William Daingerfield's children. Daingerfield, of Belvidera, near Fredericksburg, Va., was a neighbor of the Corbins.
Prominent names in the papers include Jaquelin Ambler, Leroy Anderson, Burwell Bassett, Carter Braxton, Charles Carter, Robert Cary, Robert Cholemondeley, James Lee, John Norton and Sons, John Robinson, James Semple, Benjamin Tomkins, and Benjamin Waller.
Arrangement
Chronologically arranged.
Index Terms
Persons:
Ambler, Jaquelin, 1742-1798.; Anderson, Leroy Hammond, 1770-1837.; Athawes, Edward, fl. 1750-1775.; Bassett, Burwell, d. 1793.; Braxton, Carter, 1736-1797.; Carter, Charles, 1732-1806.; Cary, Robert.; Cholemondeley, Robert.; Corbin, Richard, ca. 1708-1790.; Corbin, Richard, 1751-1819.; Daingerfield, William.; Dinwiddie, Robert, 1693-1770.; Goore, Charles.; Harrower, John, 1733 or 4-1777.; Jennings, Edmund, 1731-1819.; Lee, James.; Ludwell, Philip, 1716-1767.; Porteus, Beilby, 1731-1809.; Robinson, John, 1705-1766.; Semple, James, 1768-1831.; Tompkins, Benjamin.; Waller, Benjamin, 1716-1786.; Wormeley, Ralph, 1715-1790.
Subjects:
Tobacco industry--Virginia.; Taxation--Virginia.; Agriculture--Virginia.; Merchants--Great Britain.; Indentured servants--Virginia.; Education--Virginia.
Corporate Names:
Capel and Osgood Hanbury (Firm).; John Norton & Sons.
Contents List
- Minit of C.B. bill to B. Waller, 1763. (Box-folder 1:1)
- King's Warrant. Pay Capel Hanbury L856 for Virginia Quit Rents. Entered October 13, 1766, 28 February 1766. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Account of Richard Corbin with Capel and Osgood Hanbury, October 1762 -25 September 1766. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Lists of stock at Corbin Hall, Gatetaken, the Hill, the Dragon, Joncete, 13 October 1767. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Treasury minutes relative to forming a rent roll for Virginia, 10 December 1767. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Ambrose Carlton to Richard Corbin. Sends stock list at Moss Neck and memorandum of corn made at Moss Neck and Richland in 1768. 2 pieces, 6 February 1768. (Box-folder 1:1)
- List of negroes at the Dragon, [1768?] (Box-folder 1:1)
- James Hunter to Richard Corbin, 26 February 1768. (Box-folder 1:1)
  2 letters on one sheet, 22 and 26 February.
- Robert Cholemondeley, Auditor Office, Change Street, to Richard Corbin, Rec. Gen., 12 March 1768. (Box-folder 1:1)
- John Laforey to James Parke Farley. Receipted June 2, 1768, 15 May 1768. (Box-folder 1:1)
- List of stock at Dragon, 15 May 1768. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Contract between Benjamin Tomkins, Edmund Pendleton, John Taylor and Corbin L200 for Tomkins to erect a dam at Moss Neck, 11 June 1768. (Box-folder 1:2)
- King's Warrant. James Horrock, L100 ann. out of Va. Quit Rents as commissary, 18 June 1768. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Will of Christopher Robinson, 16 July 1768. (Box-folder 1:2)
- E. Jenings remittance on account with V. Harrison, 5 November 1768. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Account of the furniture of John Laforey as sold to the highest bidder at Blandford, 6 January 1769. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Account of negroes and stock at Richland, 8 June 1769. (Box-folder 1:2)
- A list of negroes and stock at Moss Neck, 8 June 1769. (Box-folder 1:2)
- List of stock and negroes at Jones, 17 June 1769. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Messrs. Hanbury's Dr. on account of his Majesty's Revenue, 1768-1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Messrs. Hanbury's in account with Richard Corbin, 1768-1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Accounts, 28 April 1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- List of negroes, stock, corn and tobacco at Brushwoods taken by William Hat, 9 May 1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- List of negroes and stock at Jones, 12 May 1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- R. W. Cholemondeley, Auditor's Office, to Richard Corbin, Williamsburg [copy], 18 June 1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- List of negroes and stock at George Turner's, 4 November 1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- List of negroes and stock at Daniel Hayies, 4 November 1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- List of negroes in Caroline County belonging to Richard Corbin, 29 December 1770. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Edmund Jenings, London to [Richard Corbin], 6 February 1771. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Cover sheet of above, with copy of answer from [Corbin], July 1773. (Box-folder 1:3)
- King's Warrant, entered March 6, 1773, to pay John Robinson L4000 for special services out of Va. quit rents, 8 July 1772. (Box-folder 1:3)
- List of negroes at the Land of Eden, 20 October 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- King's Warrant, John Robinson L4000 for special service out of quit rents, 20 January 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- King's Warrant, John Robinson, L4095 for special service, 23 May 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- King's Warrant, Osgood Hanbury L246 for special service, 14 June 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Account of Richard Corbin with O. Hanbury and Co., 29 June 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Osgood Hanbury, London, to Richard Corbin, Williamsburg, 2 July 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Ship bills rec'd. from Dr. Riddell, 2 August 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Richard Corbin, Jr., York, to Richard Corbin, 3 August 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- O[sgood] H[anbury] and Co., to Richard Corbin, 9 October 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Osgood Hanbury and Co., London, to Richard Corbin, 9 December 1773. (Box-folder 1:4)
- King's Warrant, John Robinson L4000 for special services, 20 January 1774. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Robert Cary & Co., London, to Colo. Richard Corbin, York River, 14 November 1774. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Encloses copy of November 14 letter, 1 December 1774. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Sam Aberchrombie to Richard Corbin, 20 February 1775. (Box-folder 1:5)
  Includes cover sheet.
- King's Warrant, Grey Cooper L4000 for special service, 16 March 1775. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Nine bills with cover sheet, 8 July 1775. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Bill of exchange. John Wilson to Charles Wilson, 16 May 1775., Printed form with mansucript insertions. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Bill of exchange. George Dobbie to Charles Wilson, 12 June 1775., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Bill of exchange. John Hunter to William Woodrop, 20 June 1775., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Bill of exchange. Henry Parry to Charles Wilson, 20 June 1775., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Bill of exchange. John Ris [?] to Thos. Hodge, 22 June 1775., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Bill of exchange. Archibald Henry to James Robinson, Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Bill of exchange. Robert Dunlap to Charles Wilson, June 1775., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:5)
- Bond. Christopher Robinson to Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley, 27 July 1775. (Box-folder 1:6)
- John Norton & Son, London, to Richard Corbin, King & Queen County, 5 September 1775. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Hanbury & Lloyds, London, to Richard Corbin,York Town, 10 April 1776. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Receipt from Oliver Towles, 1 July 1776. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Stock & utensils at Reeds & Moss Neck, 28 October 1777. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Assessment at Noss's Neck and the Reeds, 1778. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Account of the new house at Hewick, 25 March 1778. (Box-folder 1:6)
- A list of negroes at the Green Branch, 1778. (Box-folder 1:6)
- A list of negroes & stock at the Reeds, 30 May 1778. (Box-folder 1:6)
- List of negroes at Buckingham, 1 August 1778. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Deed of settlement. Griffin to Corbin, 10 December 1778. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Bond, receipted 16 September 1786, Samuel Griffin to John Tayloe Corbin, 12 December 1778. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Order. B. Collier on Richard Corbin, 5 October 1779. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Weights of tobacco now at Moss Neck, 1778. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Receipt from James Lee to John Tayloe Corbin, 8 April 1780. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Receipt from James Lee to John Tayloe Corbin, 8 April 1780. (Box-folder 1:7)
- List of stock at Parrots, Weakes's, 27 May 1780. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Receipt from Ann Spratt, 15 October 1781. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Memo on corn, 3 October 1781. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Crop & corn made at Moss Neck & Richland, 1782. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Bond. William Steptoe to Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley, 19 June 1782. (Box-folder 1:7)
- John Turberville, Hickory Hill, to Richard Corbin, Laneville, 4 January 1783. (Box-folder 1:7)
- John Robinson to Richard Corbin, Rosegill, 24 January 1783. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Account of the estate of Christopher Robinson with Cary & Co., 22 August 1783. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Wakelin Welch, London, to Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley 26 September 1783. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Order. Wakelin Welch on Ralph Wormeley, 26 September 1783. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Wakelin Welch, London, to pay Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley L10,000 30 September 1783. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Wakelin Welch, London, to Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley, York River 1 October 1783. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Receipt from Wakelin Welch to Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley for their interest, 29 November 1783., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Report. Pendleton etc. v. Hanbury & Corbin, [1784] (Box-folder 1:8)
- Power of attorney from Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley to Wakelin Welch & Wakelin Welch, Jr, 1784., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Mr. Grymes's, Ralph Wormeley to Richard Corbin, Laneville, 25 February 1784. (Box-folder 1:8)
- The Amendatory Answer of Richard Corbin to the Bill of Complaint inhibited against himself and others in the High Court of Chancery by Jacquelin Ambler and Rebecca his wife (incomplete), 8 March 1784. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Richard Corbin's Report to the Court of Chancery of the sale of Rootes' Land, 12 March 1784. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Wakelin Welch & Son, London, to [Richard Corbin], 26 July 1784. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Account of the estate of Christopher Robinson with Wakelin Welch, 22 August 1784. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Wakelin Welch & Son, London, to Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley, Urbanna, 27 September 1784. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Account of the estate of Christopher Robinson with Wakelin Welch & Son, 22 August 1785. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Wakelin Welch & Son, London, to Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley, 13 September 1785. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Corn made at Corbin Hall, 1786. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Crop of corn at Moss Neck, 1786. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Wakelin Welch & Son, London, to Richard Corbin & Ralph Wormeley, 21 March 1786. (Box-folder 1:9)
- List [of] stock at the Green branch, June 1786. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Copy of order. Robinson's administrator v. Capel, Hanbury & Richard Corbin, 14 November 1786. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Report of Richard Corbin, T. Hanbury & John Robinson (incomplete), 1787. (Box-folder 1:9)
- Wakelin Welch & Son, London, to Richard Corbin, 4 February 1788. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Wakelin Welch & Son, London, to Richard Corbin, 8 February 1788. (Box-folder 1:10)
- John Taylor, Caroline, to Richard Corbin, King and Queen County, 5 March 1788. (Box-folder 1:10)
- John Lloyd, London, to Richard Corbin, Laneville, 30 April 1788. (Box-folder 1:10)
- John Lloyd, to Richard Corbin, Laneville, 30 April 1788., Duplicate of above. (Box-folder 1:10)
- John Taylor, Caroline, to Richard Corbin, King and Queen County, 2 July 1788. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Copy of deed, Daniel Coleman & Dorrell Turner, 8 September 1788. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Ben Waller, Williamsburg, to Richard Corbin, Laneville, 14 January 1789. (Box-folder 1:10)
- George Turner, Moss Neck, to John Tayloe Corbin, Laneville, 20 January 1789. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Ben Waller, Williamsburg, to Richard Corbin, Laneville, 25 February 1789. (Box-folder 1:10)
- George Turner, Moss Neck, to John Taylor Corbin, Laneville, 6 March 1789. (Box-folder 1:10)
- John Taylor, Richmond, to Richmond Corbin, Laneville, 29 May 1789. (Box-folder 1:10)
- List of negroes at the Green Branch & Jones, 8 July 1789. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Answer. Corbin executor, Corbin v. Randolph, [1790] (Box-folder 1:11)
- Thomas Corbin to John Tayloe Corbin, Laneville, 9 April 1790. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Crop of corn made at Green Branch & Jones at Hall & Gate, 1791. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Receipted account with Col. Taylor, 24 May 1791. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Certificate of George Lee Turberville, 27 June 1791. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Jane Corbin, orphan of Gawen Corbin, made choice of George Lee Turberville as guardian, 27 September 1791. (Box-folder 1:11)
- George Lee Turberville to John Tayloe Corbin, Laneville, 13 November 1791. (Box-folder 1:11)
- George Lee Turberville to John Tayloe Corbin, Laneville, 29 December 1791. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Receipt from Robert Andrews to John Tayloe Corbin, 27 February 1792. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Certificate of George Lee Turberville, 22 March 1792. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Certificate of Orrick Chilton, 22 May 1792. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Receipt for William C. Beall, 6 June 1792. (Box-folder 1:12)
- A list of stock & negroes at Jones, 14 June 1792. (Box-folder 1:12)
- A list of stock & negroes at Green Branch, 14 June 1792. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Order. James Lee on John Tayloe Corbin receipted 28 May 1793, 18 July 1792. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Receipted account of John T. & Gawen S. Corbin with William & Mary College, 18 July 1793. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Receipt from Robert Andrews to John Tayloe Corbin, 13 March 1793. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Receipt from Richard Bingham on John Tayloe Corbin, 23 March 1793. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Bill of Lading, John Tayloe Corbin, 20 May 1793., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 1:12)
- John Tayloe Corbin to Peter Wyatt, Gloucester County, 25 May 1793. (Box-folder 1:12)
- A list of cattle & hogs at Laneville, 15 November 1793. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Crop of corn at Moss Neck & Richland, 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with the sheriff of James City County, 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted Account of Richard Corbin with Muse, 19 April 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipt from Dudley to Richard Corbin, 27 April 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Thomas Gilliat, 29 April 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account with Joseph Jackson, 29 April 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Mr. Corbin with Harry Heth, 30 April 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- William C. Bealle, Westmoreland, to the executors of John Tayloe Corbin, 23 May 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Account of Richard Corbin with John Houston, 24 May 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Account of Richard Corbin with William Larke, 31 May 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with Peter Powell, 2 June 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Richard Corbin's account with John Marshall, 1 July 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with Benj. Holland, 8 July 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with John Guest & Co., 8 July 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Mr. Corbin with James Gallagher, 11 July 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipt from George Chaplin to Richard Corbin, 9 August 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with John Coke, 30 August 1794. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with Soloman Combo, 6 September 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with Moseley and Cottart, 22 September 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Mewburn Camp (& Co.?), 29 September 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Thomas Gilliat, 30 September 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Order, receipted 13 October 1794, Alexander Irvine on Richard Corbin, 1 October 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Order, Thomas W. Lawson on Richard Corbin, 21 October 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Christopher Fry, 25 October 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with William Smith, 26 October 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with James Semple, 28 October 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipt from James Galt to Richard Corbin, 31 October 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipt from Alexander Massenberg to Richard Corbin, 12 November 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Account of Corbin with Charles Hunt, 15 November 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Lawrence Smith (Sink?), 20 November 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipt from Waddick and Edge to Thomas W. Lawson, 30 November 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipt from Oliver to Richard Corbin, 5 December 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Rookesby Roberts, 6 December 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipt from James Semple to Richard Corbin, 6 December 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Johh Keiter, 13 December 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Matthew Anderson, 17 December 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Alex Massenburg, 17 December 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Josiah Moody, 31 December 1794. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Bond, receipted 16 July 1795, Richard Corbin to John Carter Byrd, 11 May 1795. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Bond, receipted 14 January 1796, Richard Corbin & George Jackson to John Pierce, administrator of Ralph Graves, 10 June 1795., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Samuel Swann, Richmond, to Richard Corbin, Williamsburg, with account 19 August 1795. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Receipts from sundry persons, 1795. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Burwell Bassett to Richard Corbin, Williamsburg, 24 October 1795. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Account with John Didlake, 1796. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Receipt from Frances Corbin to Richard Corbin, 1 January 1796. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Thomas P. Dawson reciept from Burwell Bassett for property in and near Williamsburg for 4 January 1796 receipted account of Richard Corbin with Peter Powell, 1 January 1796. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Receipted account, Peter Powell on Richard Corbin, 22 December 1795. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Order, receipted 29 February 1796, Richard Coke on Richard Corbin, 12 January 1796. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Receipt from James Manner to Richard Corbin, 21 January 1796. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with Leroy Anderson, 1 February 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipted account of Corbin with James Wood, 2 February 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Peter Wilkinson, 5 February 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Order, Francis Monteque on Francis Corbin, 5 February 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipt from Richard Frazier to Richard Corbin, 24 February 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipt from James Ware to Richard Corbin, 26 February 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipt from Philip Barraud to Richard Corbin, 27 February 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with Robert Greenhow, 29 February 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Account of Richard Corbin with clerk of Williamsburg, March 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipted account of William C. Beall with Corbin, 5 March 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Account of Corbin with James Kidd, receipted, 3 April 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Bond. Richard Corbin & Philip Watkins to Benjamin and James Kidd, 9 April 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipt from William Bowden to Richard Corbin, 24 April 1796. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Robert Greenhow, 16 May 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipted account of Corbin with James O'Melay, 18 May 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipted account of Mrs. Maria Corbin with William D. Lewis, 8 June 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipt from Samuel Ware to Richard Corbin, 12 June 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipted account of George Turner with George Lang, 27 June 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipted account of George Turner with Leroy Anderson, 27 June 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Order from Catherine Vass on Richard Corbin receipted 15 July, 15 July 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- List of negro stock at Green Branch, 16 July 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipt from William Arthur to Richard Corbin, 29 July 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Willett & O'Connor, 13 August 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipt from John Gordon to Richard Corbin, 2 September 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with William B. Lewis, 11 October 1796. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Bond, receipted 3 June 1803, Richard Corbin to Robert & Peter Bruce, 26 November 1796., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Account of Corbin executors with sheriff of King & Queen County, 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Account of clerk with King & Queen County, 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Account of Corbin with King & Queen County Commissioners, 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Account of Richard Corbin with Peter Tinsley, 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Account of Corbin with Thomas Pinmond (Piemont?), 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with William B. Lewis, 7 May 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Account of James Trice, 14 July 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Bond, receipted 19 March 1799, Richard Corbin to John Campbell, 13 October 1797., Printed form with manuscript insertions. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Order, John Campbell on Richard Corbin, 21 October 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Account of Richard Corbin with George Taylor, 29 November 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Note to Humphrey Garrett, 30 November 1797. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Receipt. Corbin executors from sheriff of King & Queen County, 1798. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Account of fee bills paid, 1798., Coversheet. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Memo on the quantity of pork raised at Moss Neck, 1798. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Crop of corn raised at Moss Neck, 1798. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Receipt from Thomas Healy to Capt. Thomas Segar, 22 January 1798. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Rockingham County, N.C. paper relating to Laura Town, 2 February 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipted account of Corbin with William Dick, 9 February 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipt from Lewis E. Durant to Andrew Prin, 10 February 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipted account of Richard Corbin with Richard Frazier, 30 February 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipt, George Garrett to Richard Corbin, 5 March 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipted account of Corbin with Thomas Collins, 7 April 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipt from John Ferneyhough to Richard Corbin, 8 May 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Order, Ware v. Corbin executors, 15 May 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Account of the Tholengah Wood with Matthew Glenn, 19 May 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipt from John Henderson to Richard Corbin, 20 June 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipted account of Corbin with George D. Shepherd, 3 June 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Receipt from George D. Shepherd to Richard Corbin, 23 June 1798. (Box-folder 2:5)